Guide to the Papers of Jacques Judah Lyons (1813-1877), undated, 1705-1885, 1908, 1911-1914, 1917-1919, 1933, 1950 *P-15
American Jewish Historical Society, Newton Centre, MA and New York, NY
- Series I: Manuscripts, undated, 1705, 1709-1880, 1933, 1950; 3.75 linear feet. Boxes 1-6A.
  - Copy of letter sent to Benjamin Pereira at Jamaica engaging him as teacher in K.K.S.I., December 16, 1760 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Receipt for a Sefer Torah lent the Philadelphia congregation by Congregation Shearith Israel (Hebrew, translation provided from Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society), 1761 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Report of meeting of K.K.S.I. regarding appointment of trustees, June 17, 1784 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Bills received and collected of Mr. Lazarus (oversized, see Box #14), 1795 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Sale of men's seats for 3 years, August 26, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Treasurer's reports of Hayman Levy (oversized, see Box #14), 1787 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Meeting of congregation for election of 6 trustees and to obtain a new charter, June 30, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Inventory of K.K.S.I. chest, receipted by Alex. Zuntz, with note by Isaac H. Levy (oversized, see Box #14), July 25, 1784 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Inventory of real estate on Wall Street, undated (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Petition of Judah de Moseh Aguilar (Portuguese), undated (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Letter from Mrs. G. Philips regarding her husband's punishment by the congregation, April 26, 1796 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Letter from Haim Mudahy to K.K.S.I. asking for charity (Spanish, translation provided from Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society), undated (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Application of Moses Calo, Curaçao, for the post of hazan at K.K.S.I., August 1765 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Petition of Michael Jacobs for assistance, September 9, 1773 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Promissory note of M.S. Hays, July 20, 1790 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Opinion of Whitehead Hicks regarding distribution of synagogue seats, November 21, 1770 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Letter to K.K.S.I. from London (Portuguese, translation provided from Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society), February 24, 1775 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Subscription to K.K.S.I. religious school, September 7, 1793 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Synagogue account with Manuel Myers (oversized, see Box #14), 1793-1795 (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Petition of Moses Lazarus, Shochet, for increase in salary, July 28, 1771 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Call for a meeting of the congregation to elect a trustee in place of Isaac Gomez, September 13, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Petition of Isaac Da Silva for money, circa 1766 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Petition of Levy Michaels, to K.K.S.I., circa 1765 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Bill of Hayman Levy to K.K.S.I., 1788 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Letter of trustees to congregation regarding opening of Oliver Street and affect on congregation's property, undated (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Promissory note of Joshua Mendes to K.K.S.I., 1752 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Warrant to pay John Moore for building house on Mill Street, December 4, 1790 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Promissory note of Alexander Barnet, September 21, 1754 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Report of Gershom Seixas regarding religious school, November 1, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Letter of Gershom Seixas to trustees, December 27, 1809 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Letter of Gershom Seixas asking for salary increase, October 25, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Resolution regarding salary of Gershom Seixas, March 23, 1784 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Letter regarding increase in salary from G.M. Seixas, August 2, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Letter from Gershom Seixas to Manuel Myers regarding increase in salary, September 8, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Letter from Gershom Seixas to K.K.S.I. regarding his house, August 18, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Report of committee regarding house for G. Seixas, September 5, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - Letter to K.K.S.I. from Gershom Seixas regarding his contract, August 21, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - Fragment of Manuscript Minutes of Congregation Beth Elohim, Charleston, S.C., January 27, 1775 (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Contract between K.K.S.I. and Gershom Seixas regarding school (oversized, see Box #14), July 1793 (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Letters to Rev. Peixotto announcing election of Naphtali Phillips as Parnas, 1819-1821 (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - Letter announcing election of Aaron Levy as trustee of K.K.S.I., May 13, 1804 (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - Begging letter from Joseph Ben Joshua Netef Salit. Application from minutes of trustees (Hebrew), August 21, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - Letter to M.L.M. Peixotto to place Mrs. Brandley Isaacs on list of perpetual escaboth, January 15, 1826 (Box 2, Folder 151)
  - Letter from D.G. Seixas to M.L.M. Peixotto regarding Hebrew name of Mr. Solomons, June 29, 1823 (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - Judah Zuntz's application for clerk, April 12, 1801 (Box 2, Folder 153)
  - Letters to Aaron Levy from Isaac M. Gomez asking for certificate of incorporation for meeting of new trustees, July 8, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - Conversion certificate of Jacob Bar Abraham Abinu, copy made January 3, 1820 (see Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society, v. 27, p. 231-2) (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - Expenses of the congregation regarding real estate, 1819-1820, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 156)
  - Letter of thanks to J.J. Lyons, September 14, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 157)
  - Letter and reply to Mrs. De Leon regarding seat, undated (Box 2, Folder 158)
  - Letter regarding resignation of Haym M. Salomon as trustee, May 8, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 159)
  - Offers to the tsedaka (oversized, see Box #13), 1811, 1815, 1819 (Box 2, Folder 160)
  - List of offerings of Eleazer Lyons on the Bar Mitzvah of his son, 1818 (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - Book listing seats leased in synagogue, 1820 (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - Shtar Halitsah given by Edward and Henry Morrison, January 15, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Permit to K.K.S.I. from city to move remains from Oliver Street to 21stStreet, November 15, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - Map of New Bowry and 21stStreet Cemeteries, and list, undated (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Duties to the dead and dying, circa 1811 (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - Request of Simeon Levy to K.K.S.I. for matzoth, March 19, 1805 (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - Letter of Gershom Seixas regarding services to K.K.S.I., November 22, 1801 (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - Copy of bill of exchange of Haym Salomon, and letter regarding the same, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - Letter from Manuel Josephson to K.K.S.I. regarding joint letter to George Washington, December 14, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - Letter to Gov. Clinton from K.K.S.I., 1783 (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - Copy of letter of K.K.S.I. to London regarding selection of a hazan (oversized, see Box #14), March 13, 1758 (Box 3, Folder 172)
  - Letter from Newport to K.K.S.I. regarding Abraham and Mathias Cohen, two poor men, May 26, 1761 (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - Draft of letter from M. Seixas, Newport to K.K.S.I. regarding letter to Pres. Washington, July 2, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - Letter of trustees of K.K.S.I. to Newport congregation regarding joint letter to Pres. Washington (oversized, see Box #14), June 20, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - Letter from Moses Seixas, Newport, regarding joint letter to Pres. Washington, July 2, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 176)
  - Copy of letter from K.K.S.I. regarding sending money to Newport to help them build a synagogue, circa 1759 (Box 3, Folder 177)
  - Letter sent by 10 members of Newport congregation thanking K.K.S.I. for contribution for synagogue, May 28, 1759 (Box 3, Folder 178)
  - Note of Naphtali Hart promising to pay the trustees of Newport synagogue the money given by K.K.S.I., July 13, 1759 (Box 3, Folder 179)
  - Letter from congregation in Newport asking K.K.S.I. for help in building a synagogue (oversized, see Box #14), March 21, 1759 (Box 3, Folder 180)
  - Letter from Naphtali Hart, Newport, to K.K.S.I. asking for more help to finish synagogue, April 5, 1761 (Box 3, Folder 181)
  - Letter of Moses Lopez, Newport regarding subscription of New York members for furniture etc., July 25, 1762 (Box 3, Folder 182)
  - Letter from Moses Levy regarding New York congregation's agreement to pay ½ cost for return of Rev. H.H. Samuel Cohen, September 4, 1775 (Box 3, Folder 183)
  - Certificate of kosher beef sent from Newport to Surinam (Spanish), September 6, 1787 (Box 3, Folder 184)
  - Moses Seixas' accounts for Newport Congregation (oversized, see Box #14), 1784-1790 (Box 3, Folder 185)
  - Papers pertaining to burying ground (MISSING), 1728 (Box 3, Folder 186)
  - Report of committee of K.K.S.I. on several matters (oversized, see Box #14), July 24, 1791 (Box 3, Folder 187)
  - Copy of letter from Portuguese congregation, London, to K.K.S.I. regarding re-burial of dead, April 6, 1791 (Box 3, Folder 188)
  - Letter from J.J. Lyons to trustees of K.K.S.I. regarding establishment of permanent minyan, June 6, 1844 (Box 3, Folder 189)
  - Circular by committee of Hebra Hased V'Amet regarding establishment of women's Hebra, June 23, 1830 (Box 3, Folder 190)
  - Eulogy on Gershom Seixas by Naphtali Phillips, 1816 (Box 3, Folder 191)
  - List of names of some of the remains disinterred from Oliver Street and reburied in the 21stStreet cemetery, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 192)
  - Resignation of Simon Nathan as trustee, undated (Box 3, Folder 193)
  - Address to K.K.S.I. regarding Polonies Talmud Torah (oversized, see Box #14), 1804 (Box 3, Folder 194)
  - Hebrew poem on the 78thanniversary of the consecration of the 1stMill Street synagogue (Hebrew), 1808 (Box 3, Folder 195)
  - Receipt for $175. Collected for poor in Ireland, 1847 (Box 3, Folder 196)
  - Women in the congregation in the days of Hazan I.B. Seixas (oversized, see Box #14), undated (Box 3, Folder 197)
  - Letter to K.K.S.I. from K.K. B'nai Jeshurun, asking to borrow seforim and ornaments for the consecration of the synagogue (oversized, see Box #14), June 27, 1827 (Box 3, Folder 198)
  - Poll of an election held May 17, 1801 (Box 3, Folder 199)
  - Letter of Rev. Joseph J. Pinto to K.K.S.I. announcing his intention to return to Europe (oversized, see Box #14), December 22, 1765 (Box 3, Folder 200)
  - Letter of Joseph J. Pinto (Hebrew, translation provided from Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society)(oversized, see Box #14), July 11, 1759 (Box 3, Folder 201)
  - Letter from Moses Gomez who wishes to change his seat in synagogue, June 19, 1796 (Box 3, Folder 202)
  - Letter of B.S. Judah, presenting Tebah cloth, etc. for escaba for his grandfather, June 10, 1794 (Box 3, Folder 203)
  - Application of Alexander Harris to be shochet at $5 per week, January 27, 1796 (Box 3, Folder 204)
  - Hebrew Prayer at the time of revolt of the Negroes, probably in Surinam (Hebrew, translation provided from Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society), undated (Box 3, Folder 205)
  - Marriage contract of Haym Myers and Rachel Louzada (Copy of. Original sold by NMK March 26, 1987. Hebrew), 1751 (Box 3, Folder 206)
  - Letter from Jeoshua His DeCordova regarding kosher meat (Portuguese, translation provided from Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society), April 8, 1758 (Box 3, Folder 207)
  - Letter from B.S. Judah, declining to act as hatan bereshit, September 9, 1794 (Box 3, Folder 208)
  - Report of committee to inspect Hebrew school, 1794 (Box 3, Folder 209)
  - FOLDER MISSING (Box 3, Folder 210)
  - Facsimile of Jonas Phillips' citizenship certificates, 1759 (Box 3, Folder 211)
  - Order to pay G. Seixas for keeping school, December 9, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 212)
  - Letter of Simeon Levy regarding school, October 22, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 213)
  - Bills and receipts of Dr. Andrew Judah for attendance on poor of K.K.S.I., 1761-1762 (Box 3, Folder 214)
  - Letter introducing Mark Solomons, shochet, from Philadelphia, February 8, 1796 (Box 3, Folder 215)
  - Copy of letter to Moses Franks regarding hazan for K.K.S.I. (see also Item #172, March 13, 1758) (Box 3, Folder 216)
  - Papers of Ladies Army Relief Association, 1861 (Box 3, Folder 217)
  - Receipts and Bills of K.K.S.I.-General and unspecified, and others (oversized, see Box #14), 1770-1793 (Box 3, Folder 218a)
  - Accounts of K.K.S.I.-Membership, debts, bonds and interest (oversized, see Box #14) (Box 3, Folder 218b)
  - Accounts of K.K.S.I.-Building maintenance and repair (Box 3, Folder 218c)
  - Accounts of K.K.S.I.-Tzedaka Fund (oversized, see Box #14 (items 34a and 34b)) (Box 3, Folder 218d)
  - Accounts of K.K.S.I.-Salaries, 1795-1807 (Box 3, Folder 218e)
  - Papers regarding workhouse, 1855, and constitution of the American Hebrew Agricultural Association, undated, 1855-1856 (Box 3, Folder 219)
  - Memo of manuscripts and articles deposited in the cornerstone of 19thstreet synagogue of K.K.S.I.-Papers, Ladies Hebrew Benevolent Society, undated, 1843-1859 (Box 3, Folder 220)
  - Diary on Damascus persecution, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 221)
  - Letter from Palestine asking for assistance (Hebrew), 1770? (Box 3, Folder 222)
  - Traces of settlement in Bound Brook, N.J., 1840 (Box 3, Folder 223)
  - Oath of allegiance to George II by Jews in American colonies (oversized, see Box #14), 1741 (Box 3, Folder 224)
  - Letter of Jews of Amsterdam to Jews of Baltimore, regarding Jews of the Holy Land (oversized, see Box #14), 1823 (Box 3, Folder 225)
  - Petition to legislature regarding religion in free schools (oversized, see Box #14), January 7, 1813 (Box 3, Folder 226)
  - Impression from copper plate deposited in cornerstone of 2ndMill Street synagogue (Hebrew), 5577 (1817) (Box 3, Folder 227)
  - Appeal for the persecuted cretans, issued by the clergy of New York, January 14, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 228)
  - Letter from A.H. Cohen regarding dedication of synagogue, undated (Box 3, Folder 229)
  - Order to pay Aaron Levy, regarding K.K. Mikve Israel, April 30, 1804 (Box 3, Folder 230)
  - Composition in Hebrew by Rabbi Dob Pique Sung at consecration of synagogue (Hebrew), 1818 (Box 4, Folder 231)
  - Article from Harper's Monthly Magazine regarding Newport Burying Ground, August 1869 (Box 4, Folder 232)
  - Discourse on the Centennial of Neve Shalome, Surinam, by Judah A. Devries (Dutch, translation provided), 1785 (Box 4, Folder 233)
  - Part of order of service and Hebrew prayer, recommended during the revolution (Hebrew), 1776 (Box 4, Folder 234)
  - Letter from Isaac Seixas to Hayman Levy on proposed marriage of Benjamin Seixas to Zipporah Levy, November 13, 1778 (Box 4, Folder 235)
  - Form of election notice for trustees in time of Gershom Seixas, undated (Box 4, Folder 236)
  - Financial statement, Hebra Hased Ve-Amet, 1860 (Box 4, Folder 237)
  - Hebrew prayer for the consecration of the cemetery, Long Island (Hebrew), August 3, 1851 (Box 4, Folder 238)
  - Inventory of property of K.K.S.I., 1821 (Box 4, Folder 239)
  - Early bills of K.K.S.I., 1797-1799, 1806 (Box 4, Folder 239a)
  - Letters from Moise and Jacob Seixas to K.K.S.I. regarding reduction in seat costs because they are refugees (French) (French, translation provided from Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society), May 6, 1794 (Box 4, Folder 240)
  - Copy of English address given by G. Seixas after his return to New York City, 1784 (Box 4, Folder 241)
  - Resolution of Trustees, K.K.S.I. to buy ground in Beaver Street, in rear of Mill Street synagogue (oversized, see Box #14), March 21, 1797 (Box 4, Folder 242)
  - Copy of deed for land of Newport synagogue, 1760 (Box 4, Folder 243)
  - Judah Zuntz's report on the Beth Haim, March 27, 1814 (Box 4, Folder 244)
  - Clerk's list of offerings, 4thquarter (oversized, see Box #14), 1804 (Box 4, Folder 245)
  - Report of committee to make arrangements for matzah baking (oversized, see Box #14), 1819 (Box 4, Folder 246)
  - Poll of an election, March 7, 1802 (Box 4, Folder 247)
  - Poll of an election, May 16, 1802 (Box 4, Folder 248)
  - Committee report, June 20, 1819 (Box 4, Folder 249)
  - Congregational account (oversized, see Box #14), October 24, 1809 (Box 4, Folder 250)
  - Letter to J.J. Lyons from trustees, not permitting him to officiate at funeral of Bernheimer child, 1853 (Box 4, Folder 251)
  - Circular regarding Richmond congregation on Rev. Ellis Lyons, 1840 (Box 4, Folder 252)
  - Receipts and accounts of congregation, 1797-1799 (Box 4, Folder 253)
  - Notice to change constitution of K.K.S.I., July 11, 1833 (Box 4, Folder 254)
  - Letter regarding prohibition of P.J. Joachimsen from receiving mitzvah, September 19, 1860 (Box 4, Folder 255)
  - Resolution asking hazan to prepare inventory of property, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 256)
  - Letter from Thomas Hope, architect, regarding drawings for ark of new synagogue. Also includes wash drawing of canopy for ark (oversized, see Box #14), January 10, 1818 (Box 4, Folder 257)
  - Bills for congregation house, 1797-1798 (Box 4, Folder 258)
  - List of offerings, 1805 (Box 4, Folder 259)
  - Fragment of resolution regarding sale of seats, undated (Box 4, Folder 260)
  - Letters and receipts from Sir Moses Montefiore, 1850-1862 (Box 4, Folder 261)
  - Copy of letter and agreement with Mr. Solomons, shochet, undated (Box 4, Folder 262)
  - Letter of Jacob Abrahams, shochet, November 1804 (Box 4, Folder 263)
  - Sale of ship "Farmer" to Isaac M. Gomez by Joao Jose Da Silva (oversized, see Box #14), October 21, 1794 (Box 4, Folder 264)
  - Minutes of the congregation, June 11, 1820 (Box 4, Folder 265)
  - Minutes of the congregation, November 15, 1820 (Box 4, Folder 266)
  - List of offerings (oversized, see Boxes #13 and #14 (Item #s 6,44a-44j)), 1812, 1815, 1819-1820 (Box 4, Folder 267)
  - Pensions paid by K.K.S.I., 1819-1821 (Box 4, Folder 268)
  - Debts of the congregation, circa 1801 (Box 4, Folder 269)
  - Letters from Curaçao to K.K.S.I., 1818-1819 (Box 4, Folder 270)
  - Minutes of trustees meetings, 1801-1802 (Box 4, Folder 271)
  - Various bills and statements (oversized, see Box #14), 1803, 1819, 1823 (Box 4, Folder 272)
  - Letter of Ephraim Hart, declining to serve as trustee, 1801 (Box 4, Folder 273)
  - Letter and resolution of the trustees, October 18, 1833 (Box 4, Folder 274)
  - Notice of election of Benjamin Nathan, 1852 (Box 4, Folder 275)
  - Questions by trustees regarding rights of Cohanim, 1845 (Box 4, Folder 276)
  - List of bills for offerings, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 277)
  - Certificate of election of Isaac Moses as trustee, 1807 (Box 4, Folder 278)
  - Letter of trustees of Portuguese congregation, London, to K.K.S.I. regarding choosing a hazan for K.K.S.I., October 28, 1757 (Box 4, Folder 279)
  - Various notes on Newport by J.J.L. (Note: Only one folder), undated, 1873, 1877 (Box 4, Folder 280a-e)
  - Sermons by Gershom Mendes Seixas, undated, 1799, 1805, 1807 (Box 4, Folder 281)
  - Charity Sermon by Gershom Mendes Seixas, 1807 (Box 4A, Folder 281F)
  - Papers of the Jewish Theological Seminary and Scientific Institute, undated, 1852-1877 (Box 5, Folder 282)
  - Minutes of Committee on Accounts, July 6, 1820 (Box 5, Folder 283)
  - Notice of election of B. Nathan & S. Lazarus, 1854 (Box 5, Folder 284)
  - Bill for work done on synagogue, June 25, 1798 (Box 5, Folder 285)
  - Bills of Mark Solomons, shochet, 1797 (Box 5, Folder 286)
  - Bill of Israel Joel for Israel Israel, September 25, 1798 (Box 5, Folder 287)
  - Various synagogue bills, 1797-1799 (Box 5, Folder 288)
  - Poll of election, June 21, 1807 (Box 5, Folder 289)
  - Conditions and terms of leasing seats, 1832 (Box 5, Folder 290)
  - Notice concerning shochet, 1803 (Box 5, Folder 291)
  - Bills for offerings, 1789-1799 (Box 5, Folder 292)
  - Poll of an election to replace a trustee, 1806 (Box 5, Folder 293)
  - Election notices, 1850-1852, 1860 (Box 5, Folder 294)
  - List of offerings of M.L. Moses, 1820 (Box 5, Folder 295)
  - Ketubah of Hayman Levy and Sloe Myers [Copy of](Oversized, see Box #14), May 15, 1751 (Box 5, Folder 296)
  - Various bills, warrants, etc., 1807, 1812-1813, 1815, 1817-1818 (Box 5, Folder 297)
  - Minutes of meeting regarding purchase of property in Beaver Street, February 26, 1797 (Box 5, Folder 298)
  - Exercises at Polonies Talmud Torah School, 1843 (Box 5, Folder 299)
  - Letter (Ladino/Spanish)(oversized, see Box #14), 1763 (Box 5, Folder 300.1)
  - Letter to M.L.M. Peixotto, May 9, 1824 and Rachel Pinto's tombstone inscription, undated, 1824 (Box 5, Folder 300.2)
  - Service for the dedication of the new synagogue on 19thStreet (Hebrew), September 12, 1860 (Box 5, Folder 301)
  - Miscellaneous materials regarding Newport, undated, 1872 (Box 5, Folder 302)
  - Prayer for adverting Cholera (Dutch), undated (Box 5, Folder 303)
  - Letter to Rodriques Pacheco and Daniel Gomez, circa 1729 (Box 5, Folder 304)
  - Copy of 1794 bill of sale of the ship "Farmer"(see Item #264), undated (Box 5, Folder 305)
  - (FOLDER MISSING) (Box 5, Folder 306)
  - Letter from London regarding Haham Haim Mudahy (Portuguese, translation provided from Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society), February 1765 (Box 5, Folder 307)
  - Report on statement made to mayor regarding congregation's property and revenue, undated (Box 5, Folder 308)
  - Tabulation of total marriages, births, deaths, bar mitzvahs, 1840-1864 (Box 5, Folder 309)
  - Ticket to an exhibition, 1792 (Box 5, Folder 310)
  - Notice to K.K.S.I. regarding subscription for Lincoln monument, undated (Box 5, Folder 311)
  - Petition and remonstrance of G.M. Seixas, 1801 (Box 5, Folder 312)
  - Copies of letters regarding various ketubot, 1811, 1831 (Box 5, Folder 313)
  - Rhode Island Act of Disability [copy], undated, 1766 (Box 5, Folder 314)
  - Letters regarding election of trustees, 1840-1861 (Box 5, Folder 315)
  - Various congregational resolutions, 1850, 1855 (Box 5, Folder 316)
  - Copy of resolution regarding donation of N. Judah, H. Henricks and A. Touro to building of shul, 1818 (Box 5, Folder 317)
  - Correspondence with Mr. Joseph regarding organization of board, 1845 (Box 5, Folder 318)
  - Resolution regarding relief of sufferers of fire in Hague Street, 1850 (Box 5, Folder 319)
  - Certificate regarding J.J. Lyons (Dutch), February 19, 1836 (Box 5, Folder 320)
  - (ITEM MISSING, NO DESCRIPTION) (Box 5, Folder 321)
  - Congregational birth certificate of J.J. Lyons (Dutch), 1813 (Box 5, Folder 322)
  - Copy of birth certificate of J.J. Lyons (Dutch), 1813 (Box 5, Folder 323)
  - Manuscript Notebook of Lyons, containing notes on the Jews of Newport and Arnold's History of Rhode Island(Book no. 2. See Box 7. Very fragile.), circa 1870-1880 (Box 5, Folder 324)
  - (ITEM MISSING, NO DESCRIPTION) (Box 5, Folder 325)
  - Service for Thanksgiving Day, December 22, 1819 (Box 5, Folder 326)
  - Draft of letter to Sir Moses Montefiore on the death of his wife, November 22, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 327)
  - Acknowledgement of Lyons' letter by Sir Moses Montefiore, December 9, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 328)
  - Draft of letter by J.J. Lyons to Sir Moses Montefiore, sending him £15 for the Jews of Palestine, and acknowledgement, 1854 (Box 5, Folder 329)
  - Copy of bill of costs for Louis Gomez's denization, 1705 (Box 5, Folder 330)
  - Abstract of subject index of N.Y. State Library, Part 1, 1872 (Box 5, Folder 331)
  - Service in Hebrew on the occasion of the visit of (Gov?) Abraham Defehr of Surinam to the synagogue. Arranged by Tobia B. Abraham Mordecai (Hebrew), 1823 (Box 6, Folder 332)
  - Unsigned appeal for funds for Beth Shalome synagogue, Richmond, March 1822 (Box 6, Folder 333)
  - Copy of letter from J.J. Lyons to Sir Moses Montefiore enclosing bill of exchange for Palestinian Jews, 1854 (Box 6, Folder 334)
  - Ketubah of Sabato Morais and Esther Weil (Hebrew), 1855 (Box 6, Folder 335)